abt.com 2019-07-23

# Abt Privacy Policy

Abt respects each and every one of our customers' right to privacy. We have built our reputation on service and taking care of our customers beyond their expectations, and we will continue to provide these levels of service for many years to come.

This notice describes the privacy policy applicable to Abt.com. It addresses:

  1. What information is being collected from you through the website, how it is used, and with whom it is shared.
  2. What choices you have regarding the use of your information.
  3. The security measures we have instituted to protect your information.
  4. What you may do if you have concerns about us honoring this policy.

If you feel that we are not abiding by this policy, or have questions or concerns about the use of your information or this policy, please call us at 888-228-5800, or e-mail us at privacy@abt.com. If you prefer, you can also send your message via U.S. mail to the following address:

Abt Electronics, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy  
1200 N. Milwaukee Ave.  
Glenview, IL 60025

**Updates to our Privacy Policy**

Our Privacy Policy may be updated occasionally and the use of information which we gather now is subject to this Policy. Please check this page periodically as you continue to use our site to see if any changes have been made. We will notify you of any material changes to this Privacy Policy by posting a notice on our website at www.abt.com for a reasonable period of time after such changes are made that this Privacy Policy has been updated. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 04/19/2019. The Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon posting on the Service. Your continued use of the Service after the posting of the updated Privacy Policy establishes your agreement to abide and be bound by it.

## Information Collection, Use, and Sharing

We are the sole owners of the information collected on this website. We will not sell this information to anyone. We will not share your information with any third-party, other than as described in this policy. Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via e-mail to tell you about our company, products, and services. Abt.com can use your personal information for the purposes of preventing fraud or other prohibited activities and comply with potential requests of law enforcement.

Please see the following details.

### Orders and Accounts

We request information from you when you place an order or register for an account on Abt.com. Personal information that we collect depends on how you use Abt.com. At our checkout or registration page, you must provide your contact information (like your name, shipping address, email address, and telephone number) and financial information (like credit card number and expiration date). When you are completing an order, you are opted into our mailing list. You have the option to opt out of our mailing list by un-marking the checkbox at the opt-in screen. You also have the option of allowing Abt.com to store your login information by marking or unmarking the “remember me” box at the login screen.

Contact information is used to fill your order, notify you of its status, and contact you if we have questions regarding your order. The financial information that is collected is used only to bill you for products that you purchase and is not shared with any third party. All credit card payments are processed to encrypt and protect your financial information throughout and beyond the checkout process.

### Cookies

Our site uses "cookies." A cookie is a small piece of data that your browser holds in memory or stores in a special file on your hard drive. These small pieces of data equip us to improve our customers' experience on Abt.com through helping our server remember you. Abt.com uses several types of 1st party cookies. A “session cookie” stores temporary information that is erased when you close your browser or turn off your computer. A “persistent cookie” allows Abt.com to recognize you when you return to the website and it remains stored on your computer until you delete it. A persistent cookie is used to store your password so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Most internet browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. If you reject cookies, Abt.com will not be able to recognize your account or customize your browsing experience to fit your expressed interests.

While using Abt.com, we may automatically collect information such as your IP address, browser information, device information, and when, how, and how long you used the website. More information about the use of cookies on our site is available here (<https://www.abt.com/help/secure-shopping-guarantee>).

Abt.com may use Google Analytics to monitor user’s activity on the site and assist with advertising. To learn more about how Google Analytics collects and processes data, please visit <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>.

Additionally, this website uses Mouseflow, a third-party analytics tool, to track page content and click/touch, movement, scroll, and keystroke activity. You can opt out at <https://mouseflow.com/opt-out/>.

Mobile Device: If you access and use Abt.com through a mobile device, Abt may collect your device information and geo-location to assist us in completing your order. At any time, you may choose to deny Abt.com from accessing your location by changing your location settings within your device settings.

### Third Parties and Sharing Information

Abt maintains business relationships with a select amount of authorized business partners. For your security or benefit, we may share information about you and your transactions with other companies for reasons including identity verification, fraud prevention, legal compliance, order fulfillment, processing credit card payments, shipping, and warranty purposes. With your consent, Abt shares your information with our marketing partners who serve advertising, send emails and push notifications, and distribute catalogs on our behalf. Abt.com also provides aggregate information to some of our business partners, which does not allow for you to be personally identified. For more information about the companies with whom Abt shares customer information or to opt out, please contact us using the contact information described in this Policy. What goes on during the browsing of other sites is not the responsibility of Abt.

Third Party Transaction Data: If you visit Abt.com from a third-party website, it is possible for that website to access your specific transaction information. When you enter Abt.com through a link from another website, that website may give you a unique identifier such as a code or cookie. Any transaction made on Abt.com while this code or cookie is active will result in that transaction being reported back to the third party site. Abt.com will only report information that is not personally-identifiable such as the date of the transaction, the product(s) purchased and the amount of money spent. Abt.com will not send any information to these third parties that, alone, will allow them to personally identify you. If the third party site has previously collected your personally identifiable information on their own, they may be able to personally identify you by combining their gathered information with the information sent by Abt.com. You should verify how each third party site uses this information by reading the privacy policy that each third party site has posted on their site.

Credit Card Companies and Shipping Companies: When you buy something from Abt.com while using a credit card, we send your name, billing address and the amount of your purchase to your credit card company to verify and authorize the purchase. Similarly, your name, shipping information, and telephone number must be provided to third-party shipping companies such as UPS, Pilot, and Custom to deliver your purchase.

### Links

This site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our customers to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of other sites, who may collect personally identifiable information. If you register for an account or complete an order on Abt.com by connecting through another service, you allow us to use the public information from that connected account to help complete your Abt.com profile.

Third Party Checkout Links: Abt.com uses PayPal and FlexShopper on our site as third-party checkout links. If you use either of these two links to checkout, your name, billing and shipping addresses, and other information requested by that payment service is transferred to us from your PayPal or FlexShopper account in order to check out of Abt.com without having to re-enter that same information.

### Blogs, Reviews, and Forums

Abt.com also may sometimes offer publicly-accessible blogs, customer reviews, or forums. Any information that is voluntarily provided by you in a blog, review, or forum may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your Personal Information from blogs, customer reviews, or forums from Abt.com, please contact us using the contact information described in this Policy. Please note that in certain cases we may be unable to remove your Personal Information.

### Mailing List, Surveys, and Contests

We maintain a mailing list in order to provide customers with information about our company, products, and services. Upon your initial purchase at Abt, you will be subscribed to Abt’s mailing list. You may choose not to receive future mailings from us through deleting your name from our mailing list here: <https://www.abt.com/resources/pages/unsubscribe.php>. (Please note that in the event you place an order, you will continue to receive e-mail from us concerning your transaction even if you have unsubscribed from our mailing list.) If you prefer, you can also send your request via U.S. mail to the following address:

Abt Electronics, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy  
1200 N. Milwaukee Ave.  
Glenview, IL 60025

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip code). We use contact information from our surveys to provide customers with information about our company, and we also use survey information to monitor and improve customers' use of, and satisfaction with, this site. Participation in surveys is completely voluntary.

We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (such as name and e-mail address). We use this contact information to contact winners and provide information about our company. Participation in contests is completely voluntary.

### Children’s Online Privacy Policy

Consistent with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, Abt.com does not knowingly collect any Personal Information from children under 13 without prior parental consent. If you make a purchase on Abt.com, you are representing that you are an adult. If you are a child under the age of 13, you must ask your parent or guardian to assist you in using Abt.com. If Abt learns that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personal information online without parental consent, we will take all reasonable measures to delete the information as soon as possible and not to use such information for any purpose, except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required or allowed by law.

### Minor California Residents

If you are an Abt.com account holder who resides in California and is under the age of 18, you have the right to request the removal of unwanted information that you publicly post on Service. To request removal of information, please contact us using the contact information described in this Policy. Abt will ensure that your information is not publicly accessible on Abt.com, but your information may not be completely removed from our systems.

### Visitors From Outside of the United States of America

Abt.com is hosted in the United States. If you are visiting Abt.com from outside of the United States of America, your information may be stored, processed, or shared in the United States of America in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable USA laws. Please be aware that data protection laws in the United States of America may be different than laws than the country that you are visiting from. By using Abt.com, you consent to share your information with us only for the purposes described in this Policy.

### Retention of Personal Information

Abt retains Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by applicable law.

### Access and Choices

You may always choose not to provide us with information, although you will need to provide information in order to place an order.

To learn what contact information we have on file for you, and to update this information, please contact us at 888-228-5800. If you have created an account at Abt.com, you may log into it at <https://www.abt.com/resources/pages/account.php?screen=login> , where you may review your history of orders placed through our website, track your order's delivery status, edit your personal information, change your password, and review and modify your stored billing and shipping information.

As described above, you may unsubscribe from our mailing list so that you will no longer receive promotional materials and direct mail. (Please note that, if you place an order, you will continue to receive e-mail from us concerning your order even if you have unsubscribed from our mailing list.)

Additionally, as described above, you may limit or deactivate cookies, as well as opt out of a third-party analytics tool.

### Security

We scan our site daily for threats and vulnerabilities.

To know more about how Abt.com keeps your data secure, please see our Secure Shopping Guarantee, described here (<https://www.abt.com/help/secure-shopping-guarantee>). This page's "Frequently Asked Questions" section addresses how you can know if a website is secure as well as the security measures in place at our checkout. To verify that you are on a secure page on our site, look for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or "https" at the beginning of the address of the webpage.

***
